In this video we're going to look at how
to enter in receivables, cash receipts
in Dynamics SL, and compare that to the
experience of entering those customer
payments in Dynamics 365 Business
Central.
In my SL system, I'll go to accounts
receivable and the payment application
screen to enter a cash receipt and apply
that payment we received from one of our
customers.
I'll go ahead and select the customer
that sent us the payment.
Enter the customer payment number as
well as the payment amount.
I can then select the auto apply tab and
auto apply button, or I can find the
invoice or invoices the customer is
paying in the grid below.
Once I have found the invoice, I can
enter the amount to apply in the grid
and then save and release the batch.
Now let's see how we can enter in cash
receipts in Business Central.
To create customer payments in Business
Central, we'll select the search icon
and enter in the cash receipts journals.
Once the search result appears, we can
go ahead and select it from the list.
In the cash receipts journal, we can
record a payment for a specific
customer, Trey Research.
Change the account type to customer and
select our customer, Trey Research.
Once I've selected the customer, I can
navigate over to the apply to documents
number column by selecting the lookup.
Here I can see all of the outstanding
invoices the customer currently has with
us.
I can go ahead and find the invoice,
select it, and then choose okay.
You can see how the payment amount has
automatically defaulted in for us, and I
can post my cash receipt.
In addition to cash receipts journals,
you can also use the customer register
payments window to record customer
payments.
Again, I'll select the search icon and
this time type in customer register
payments and select it from the search
results.
In this window, we can see all
outstanding invoices for all of our
customers. However, we want to filter
the list down to just see the
outstanding invoices for Trey Research.
I'll select Trey Research and then
filter on that value.
Now we can see only the invoices for
Trey Research.
I can find and select a single invoice
that the customer sent a payment for.
Select the checkbox and it will
automatically enter in the amount and
date received. Then I go ahead and post
the payment once everything has been
entered correctly.
If the customer was sending a payment
for more than one invoice, I can select
multiple invoices
in the window and then back under
posting select to post as a lump sum
payment.
In this video, we've seen how Business
Central provides a simple and easy way
to record customer payments, allowing
for a more streamlined cash receipt
process.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.